Despite what you may get taught about the free market in undergraduate economics,
على الرغم من ما قد يتم تدريسه حول السوق الحرة في الاقتصاد الجامعي،
everything in the real business world takes place within a framework established
فإن كل شيء في عالم الأعمال الحقيقي يحدث ضمن إطار
by governments at several levels, local, state, and federal.
أنشأته الحكومات على عدة مستويات، المحلية والولائية والفيدرالية.
>> In fact, it's almost impossible to start a business without falling under one
>> في الواقع، يكاد يكون من المستحيل بدء عمل تجاري دون الوقوع تحت
set of rules or another, and guess what?
مجموعة واحدة من القواعد أو غيرها، وتخمين ماذا؟
You're the one that's responsible for knowing what they are.
أنت الشخص المسؤول عن معرفة ما هي عليه
>> As for the types of enterprises most prone to government regulation,
>> فيما يتعلق بأنواع المؤسسات الأكثر عرضة للتنظيم الحكومي،
these are the ones that affect either public safety or the environment.
فهي تلك التي تؤثر إما على السلامة العامة أو على البيئة.
So, if you are manufacturing anything, transporting people, making food,
لذا، إذا كنت تصنع أي شيء، تنقل الناس، تصنع الطعام،
or selling anything people ingest,
أو تبيع أي شيء يتناوله الناس،
expect to spend a lot of time talking to the folks downtown.
تتوقع قضاء الكثير من الوقت في التحدث إلى الناس في وسط المدينة.
>> And here's a big caution flag.
>> وهنا علم الحذر الكبير.
Failing to have right permit or
الفشل في الحصول على تصريح أو
license can mean being shut down, fined, or possibly even going to jail.
ترخيص صحيح يمكن أن يعني أن يتم إغلاقه أو تغريمه أو ربما حتى الذهاب إلى السجن.
So, check out those rules and regulations beforehand.
لذلك، تحقق من تلك القواعد واللوائح مسبقا.
Now, here's another interesting place the government gets involved in your budding
الآن، هنا مكان آخر مثير للاهتمام تشارك فيه الحكومة في
business, what the name of your business is and who actually runs it.
عملك في مهدها، ما هو اسم عملك ومن يديره في الواقع.
Here are the ideas that customers and
فيما يلي الأفكار التي
others have a right to know who might be lurking behind the shingle you hang.
يحق للعملاء والآخرين معرفة من قد يكون يتربص وراء لوحة المفاتيح التي تعلقها.
If you're doing business under the name, Sarah's Cupcakes,
إذا كنت تقوم بأعمال تجارية تحت اسم، الكعك سارة،
that's all find and good.
وهذا هو كل شيء تجد وجيد.
But even if your name is Sarah, you're going to have to file what's called a DBA,
ولكن حتى لو كان اسمك هو سارة، سيكون لديك لتقديم ما يسمى DBA،
or a "doing business as" form, usually with the county and
أو «ممارسة الأعمال التجارية» نموذج، عادة مع المقاطعة
publish and announcement in a local paper, record or online.
ونشر والإعلان في ورقة محلية، سجل أو على الانترنت.
The broader point is this, it's your job to figure out
النقطة الأوسع هي أن عملك هو معرفة
what regulations you will have to abide by if you start a new business.
ما هي اللوائح التي يجب عليك الالتزام بها إذا بدأت نشاطًا جديدًا.
Another way your enterprise will interact with the government,
طريقة أخرى سوف تتفاعل مؤسستك مع الحكومة،
is through the taxes you will have to pay.
هي من خلال الضرائب التي سيتعين عليك دفعها.
I know Alex has covered this topic in some detail.
وأنا أعلم أن اليكس قد غطت هذا الموضوع في بعض التفاصيل.
But let me share with you a personal story that makes an important point about
ولكن اسمحوا لي أن أشارككم قصة شخصية تجعل نقطة مهمة حول
understanding your tax obligations.
فهم التزاماتك الضريبية.
When I was in high school,
عندما كنت في المدرسة الثانوية،
I launched a business developing video games that continued into college.
أطلقت مشروعا لتطوير ألعاب الفيديو التي استمرت في الكلية.
One of the clients I had found had a demand for a very large volume of
واحد من العملاء كنت قد وجدت كان الطلب على حجم كبير جدا من
very simple games, and I couldn't keep up with the programming myself.
الألعاب بسيطة جدا، وأنا لا يمكن مواكبة البرمجة نفسي.
Being the enterprising entrepreneur I am, I rounded up all the kids in
كوني رجل أعمال مغامر أنا، قمت بتقريب جميع الأطفال
the neighborhood and taught them to code games.
في الحي وعلمتهم لألعاب الكود.
We wrote a lot of games and generated more than $50,000 in sales.
كتبنا الكثير من الألعاب وولدت أكثر من 50،000 دولار في المبيعات.
And I paid my apprentice software engineers cash for their work.
ودفعت لمهندسي البرامجيات المتدربين نقوداً لعملهم
As it turns out, there was a lot of tax paperwork I should've done
كما اتضح، كان هناك الكثير من الأوراق الضريبية التي كان يجب أن أقوم بها
to handle this correctly, but I had not bothered to research.
للتعامل مع هذا بشكل صحيح، ولكن لم أكن قد ازعجت للبحث.
So it was that I soon found myself sitting in my shorts and sandles squirming
لذلك كان ذلك أنني سرعان ما وجدت نفسي جالسا في بلدي السراويل القصيرة والصندل التدفق بشكل
uncomfortably in a stuffy government office, while a bespeckled IRS auditor in
غير مريح في مكتب حكومي متجهم الوجه، في حين أن مدقق مصلحة الضرائب bespeckled في
an intimidating suit browsed through a shoe box of hopelessly confused notes
دعوى مخيفة تصفحها من خلال مربع الأحذية من الملاحظات الخلط ميؤوس منها
about cash payments to programmers to young to be legally hired.
حول المدفوعات النقدية للمبرمجين الشباب ليكون قانونيا استأجروا
To his credit, and perhaps to counter Reagan's pessimism,
ولربما لمواجهة تشاؤم ريغان،
the auditor looked across at the nervous teenage entrepreneur and
نظر مراجع الحسابات عبر رجل الأعمال المراهق العصبي
said, everything seems to be in order here, Mr. Autrey.
وقال، يبدو أن كل شيء على ما يرام هنا، السيد أوتري.
But with emphasis, he also added, do not let this happen again.
ولكن مع التركيز، وأضاف أيضا، لا تدع هذا يحدث مرة أخرى.
>> I think this tax story offers up a pretty good segue to the whole subject of
>> أعتقد أن هذه القصة الضريبية تقدم ما يصل segue جيدة جدا للموضوع كله من
employees.
الموظفين.
When you pay other people to do work for you, you are opening yourself up to
عندما تدفع لأشخاص آخرين للقيام بعمل من أجلك، فإنك تفتح نفسك
a whole nest of new regulations, liabilities and taxes.
لعش كامل من اللوائح والالتزامات والضرائب الجديدة.
In some cases, you maybe able to pay folks cash or
في بعض الحالات، ربما كنت قادرا على دفع الناس نقدا أو
the equivalent in an agreed rate and send them on their way.
ما يعادلها في سعر متفق عليه وإرسالهم في طريقهم.
However, if this amount exceeds a certain limit in the United States,
ومع ذلك، إذا تجاوز هذا المبلغ حد معين في الولايات المتحدة،
the last time I checked it was still under $1,000.
آخر مرة تحققت منه كان لا يزال أقل من 1،000 دولار.
The American Internal Revenue Service requires
تطلب
you to send these contract workers a 1099 form at the end of the year
منك دائرة الإيرادات الداخلية الأمريكية إرسال نموذج 1099 إلى هؤلاء العمال المتعاقدين في نهاية العام
to insure that they don't skip out on paying their taxes.
للتأكد من أنهم لا يتجاوزون دفع ضرائبهم.
The other possibility is you actually hire some people as employees.
الاحتمال الآخر هو أنك توظف بعض الناس كموظفين
However once you do that, you are exposed to a lot more rules involving
ولكن بمجرد قيامك بذلك، فإنك تتعرض إلى قواعد أكثر
how they are paid, how much they are paid,
بكثير تتضمن كيفية دفع أجورهم، وكم تدفع لهم،
the number of hours they can work, when they get breaks and a whole lot more.
وعدد الساعات التي يمكنهم العمل، وعندما يحصلون على فترات راحة وأكثر من ذلك بكثير.
Of course all of this is too complex to review here.
بالطبع كل هذا معقد للغاية بحيث لا يمكن مراجعته هنا.
But before you hire any employees, research all of these rules.
ولكن قبل أن تقوم بتوظيف أي موظفين، قم بالبحث عن كل هذه القواعد.
Key tip here is, talk to an accountant.
المعلومة الرئيسية هنا هي التحدث إلى محاسب
And now on a similar note, let's finish up this part of the lesson and
والآن على ملاحظة مشابهة، دعونا ننهي هذا الجزء من الدرس
talk a bit about the various legal forms you can choose for your business.
ونتحدث قليلاً عن الأشكال القانونية المختلفة التي يمكنك اختيارها لنشاطك التجاري.
This is gonna vary widely depending on what country you live in.
هذا سيختلف بشكل كبير اعتماداً على البلد الذي تعيش فيه
>> But here's the big point.
>> ولكن هنا نقطة كبيرة.
How you organize your enterprise in a legal structure will have a big impact,
سيكون لكيفية تنظيم مؤسستك في هيكل قانوني تأثير كبير،
both on your own personal liability, should something go wrong, and
سواء على مسؤوليتك الشخصية، إذا حدث خطأ ما،
the level of taxes you may have to pay.
ومستوى الضرائب التي قد تضطر إلى دفعها.
>> So check out this angle carefully.
>> حتى تحقق من هذه الزاوية بعناية.
And if you're in the United States and your business has any potential for
وإذا كنت في الولايات المتحدة وعملك لديه أي إمكانية
generating liability, you may wanna consider the safety of either a regular
لتوليد المسؤولية، قد ترغب في النظر في سلامة إما
corporation or a limited liability corporation, the so-called LLC.
شركة عادية أو شركة ذات مسؤولية محدودة، ما يسمى شركة ذات مسؤولية محدودة.
>> Now, when you're ready, please move on to Part 3 of this lesson.
>> الآن، عندما تكون مستعدًا، يرجى الانتقال إلى الجزء الثالث من هذا الدرس.
[MUSIC]
[ موسيقى]